# MAJID ALI

+919451410991

ermajid2006@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated technical professional combining 9 years of IT –related experience for NIC with solid background in daily systems operations, network performance monitoring, and technical support/ troubleshooting, track record of excellent interpersonal skills, effectively communicating technical information to all levels of staff and management.

Other Knowledge of Classified Communication, LAN Management, Troubleshooting/Corrective Action, IT Infrastructure Analysis, OS & Software Installations, Active Directory.

## **Nature of Projects:**

NICNET & NKN – Providing Internet connectivity to all government bodies.

**Video Conferencing** – Conducting VC's for the government officials.

NIC Service Desk - Providing Technical Support, Troubleshooting and training to

all Government Bodies related to their project.

Other Projects – Vahan & Sarathi, e-Hostipal, e-Office, e-Prison, e-Samiksha,

Land Record, e-Panchayat, e-Court, Mnrega.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

May 2014 to Till Date **WIPRO TECHNOLOGIES LTD.** 

**Designation: Associate - Network Management** 

**Project: NICNET & NKN Project of National Informatics** 

Centre (NIC)

May 2012 to Apr 2014 TULIP TELECOM LTD.

**Designation : Network Operator Cum Field Engineer Project: NICNET & NKN Project of National Informatics** 

Centre (NIC)

SEP 2008 to Apr 2012 HCL INFOSYSTEM LTD.

**Designation: Associate** 

**Project: NICNET & NKN Project of National Informatics** 

Centre (NIC)

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

• 2007 → B.TECH in COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGG. From UPTU LUCKNOW

• 2000 → Intermediate (Science)

From UP BOARD ALLAHABAD

• 1997 → Highschool (Science)

From UP BOARD ALLAHABAD

#### SOFTWARE AWARENESS

• Plateform: Windows NT/2000/2003/XP, VISTA/7/8/10, Linux

- Hardware: Printers, Servers, Routers, Firewalls
- Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Exchange
- **Protocols/Systems/Standards:** TCP/IP, Information Security

## TRAINING ATTENDED & PASSED

- Done the project "Peer2Peer Network & Tools" on Linux using Java and MySQL database engine.
- Industrial Training from QRAT, A COMPUTER GROUP, LUCKNOW for one month
  - in 2005 Worked as Project Trainee on the project "COMPANY INFORMATION MANAGEMENT SYSTEM" using VISUAL BASIC & ORACLE.
- Seminar delivered on "ANTI PIRACY MP3 PLAYER".
- Done the project on "Library Management" & "Hospital Management" DBMS, ORACLE DATABASE & VISUAL BASIC.

## **Personal Details**

- Father's Name Mr. Sabir Ali
- Date of Birth 01.Jul.1981
- Marital Status Married.
- Language Known English, Hindi & Urdu.
- Nationality Indian.
- Passport No. G6348798
- Date of Expiry On Renewal
- Driving License UP3020150002994
- Pan No. AKQPA1240G
- Permanent Address 417, Saray Thok East Hardoi, U.P (India).

(Majid Ali.) 13<sup>th</sup> June 2018